Morthond !Morthond !Morthond !
Morthond! Morthond! Morthond!
Morthond获胜。
Morthond wins.
Pelele !
Pelele!
Agado !
Agado!
Pelele !
Pelele!
Pelele获胜。
Pelele wins.
Agnim! Cord!
cord获胜!
Cord wins!
Morthond !Pelele !
Morthond! Pelele!
Morthond获胜!
Morthond wins!
Cord! Morthond!
先生们，这是最后一场比赛。
Gentlemen, this is the final contest.
Morthond !Morthond !Morthond !
Morthond! Morthond! Morthond!
Morthond是赢家。
Morthond is the winner.
你，呃，犯了个错误。
You've, uh, made a mistake.
你把勋章给错人了。
You gave the medallion to the wrong man.
这是你的颜色吗?
Is this your color?
不。
No.
没有错误。
There was no error.
你在他倒下后打了他。
You hit him after he was down.
规矩是有的，而你违反了。
There are rules, and you have broken them.
你几乎违反了比赛的每一条规则。
You have chosen to break almost every rule of the contest.
你不穿战衣，就不属于任何团体。
You wear no fighting clothes, you belong to no group.
我自己的男人。
Lam my own man.
既然你只需要你自己，为什么还要来这里?
Then why have you come here if you need no one but yourself?
为了获得找到泽坦并击败他的权利，我走了很长一段路
L've come a long way to compete for the right to find zetan and defeat him
看看他看守的书里有什么。
and to see what is in a book he guards.
你对泽坦和他的启蒙之书了解多少?
What do you know of zetan and his book of enlightenment?
只知道这是一本书。
Only that it's a book.
它包含了世界上所有的智慧。
That it contains all the wisdom of the world.
科德，被选中寻找并击败泽坦人的人必须有能力用蜘蛛的网绑住大象。
Cord, he who is chosen to find and defeat zetan must have the ability to bind an elephant with the web of a spider.
而不是用一脚打晕他。
Not stun him with a kick.
摩蒙德被选中了!
Morthond has been chosen!
Morthond是个舞者!
Morthond is a dancer!
我一个战士!
L'm a fighter!
Morthond控制住了自己。
Morthond has controlled himself.
你还不是我们需要的锤炼武器。
You are not yet the tempered weapon that we need.
走吧!
Go!
现在!
Now!
首先一个问题。
One question first.
为什么你派去的其他人都没回来?
Why have all the others you've sent never returned?
一路上的考验是严峻的。
The trials along the way are severe.
泽坦已经证明了自己是无敌的。
Zetan has proved himself so far to be invincible.
那是因为你没有派对人来!
It is because you have never sent the right man!
但我能打败他!
But I can defeat him!
Cord!
你不能去。
You will not go.
我会打败这个无敌的泽坦人!
I will defeat this invincible zetan!
我要看看书里有什么!
And I will see what is in the book!
一年前，我发誓保持沉默。
One year ago, i took a vow of silence.
你什么时候弄坏的?
When did you break it?
现在!你为什么跟踪我?
Now! Why are you following me?
你生气是因为我打败了你。
You're angry because I defeated you.
你没有打败我!
You didn't defeat me!
你违反了规则!
You broke the rules!
又打我!
Fight me again!
它没有任何作用。
It serves no purpose.
你生来就没有大脑!打击我!
You were born without a brain! Fight me!
但我想帮你，不是杀你。
But I want to help you, not kill you.
我要找的是泽坦。
It's zetan I'm after.
重要的是吃水果，而不是怎么吃。
The important thing is eating the fruit, not how you get to it.
然后吃饭。
Eat then.
我的名字是科德。
My name is cord.
我在找一个叫泽坦的武术家。
L'm looking for a great martial artist called zetan.
你鼻子附近有一只蜜蜂。
There's a bee near your nose.
你是谁?
Who are you?
昨晚，我看到你创造了奇迹。
Last night, i saw you perform miracles.
如果泽坦的技能比你还强，我还没准备好接受他。
If zetan's skills are even greater than yours, i- I'm not ready for him.
以我所有的训练和双眼，在你面前我一秒钟都活不下去。
With all my training and both my eyes, I couldn't survive one second against you.
我的能力不是为了给你留下好印象。
My skills are not there to impress you.
我得到它!
L've got it!
现在我知道了!
Now I know!
你zetan。我才是瞎的那个!
You're zetan. I'm the one who's blind!
你是zetan吗?
Are you zetan?
不管你认为我是什么，或者想让我成为什么，我。
Whatever you think I am, or want me to be, lam.
当我的老师。
Be my teacher.
解释你做什么。我想练习。
Explain what you do. I want to practice.
把两只鸟拴在一起，即使它们有四只翅膀，它们也不能飞。
Tie two birds together, and though they have four wings- they cannot fly.
那我就跟着你看。
Well, I'll just follow you and watch.
我也不会说话打扰你。
And I won't annoy you by talking.
我可以保持沉默，相信我。
I can be silent, believe me.
他们说泽坦是一本书的守护者。
They say zetan's the guardian of a book.
他得了这病很多年了。
He's had it for many years.
你知道这本书吗?知道是什么吗?
Do you know anything about this book? Know what it is?
你觉得会很重要吗?
Do you, uh, think it could be important?
一个人年复一年地守护着一本书，哪个更重要?
Ifa man guards a book year after year, which is more important?
是人还是书?
The man or the book?
这就是秘密吗?
Is that the secret?
猴子想绕着你转——你不让——你不停地转。
The monkey tried to circle you- and you wouldn't let him- you kept turning.
猴子的方法就是装傻。
The way of the monkey is to play the fool.
当你嘲笑他的滑稽动作时，他从背后咬你。
While you laugh at his antics, he bites you from behind.
揭下他的自负，你就暴露了一个伪装成猴子的懦夫。
Unmask his ego, and you expose a coward disguised as a monkey.
L将研究它们。
L'll study them.
我会非常仔细地观察他们。
I'll watch them very carefully.
你已经模仿得很好了。
You already imitate their chattering perfectly.
哈!
Huh!
我没理由跟猴子打架。
I don't have any reason to fight monkeys.
这个教训没有价值。
This lesson has no value.
人是按照自己适合学习的程度来学习的。
One is taught in accordance to one's fitness to learn.
我要把舌头扯出来，把它
I'll tear my tongue out and put it-
morthond !等等!是Cord!
morthond! Wait! It's cord!
我给我的兄弟们带来了耻辱。
I have brought disgrace on my brotherhood.
这是Zetan干的?
Zetan did this?
Morthond,回答我!这是怎么发生的?
Morthond, answer me! How did this happen?
第一次审判。
The first trial.
是什么?
What was it?
Morthond，第一次审判是什么?在哪里?
Morthond, what was the first trial? Where?
猴子。
Monkey.
cord。大奖章。
Cord. The medallion.
把它。
Take it.
有什么可以帮你的吗，morthond?
How can I help you, morthond?
帮助我光荣地死去。
Help me die with honor.
猴子的方法119玩傻瓜。
The way of the monkey 119 to play the fool.
揭下他的自负，你就暴露了一个伪装成猴子的懦夫。
Unmask his ego, and you expose a coward disguised as a monkey.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我的名字是科德。
My name is cord.
你的乞食碗在哪里?
Where is your begging bowl?
我不是来求你的。
L'm not here to beg.
你不是来求我的吧?
You're not here to beg?
我是来接受初审的。
L'm here to face the first trial.
然后你会乞求。
Then you will beg.
你是哪个学校的?
What school do you come from?
嗯?没有学校。
Hmm? No school.
没有学校!
No school!
我来自我自己。
I come from myself.
啊!他是自己来的!
Ah! He comes from himself!
一个没有母亲的男人!
A man with no mother!
你在找什么，没有母亲的男人吗?
What are you looking for, man with no mother?
什么?
What?
我想找到泽坦。
I want to find zetan.
你以为要找到他就得跟我打吗?
And you think that to find him you must fight me, huh?
是的，你们用的是哪种公认的打法?
Yes, what acknowledged style of fighting do you use?
我的风格。
My style.
听我说，创造自己的人。
Listen to me, man who creates himself.
回去……你来时的样子，平静的样子。
Go back... The way you came, in peace.
我不想回去。
I don't want to go back.
除非我必须找到泽坦，否则我不想和你战斗。
And I don't want to fight you unless I have to to find zetan.
泽塔就在我的另一边。
Zeta n is far away on the other side of me.
要找到他，你必须先穿过……我!
To reach him, you must first pass through... Me!
如果我绕着你走呢?
What if I just walk around you?
事情不是这样的!
That is not in the order of things!
是的，如果我是你的审判，那我就是你的审判。
Yes, if I am your trial, then I am your trial.
你不能绕过我。
You cannot walk around me.
那我就得和你决斗了。
Then l'll have to fight you.
是的。
Yes.
告诉我去泽坦的路。
Now tell me the way to zetan.
拥抱西风，直到你来到一片荒野。
Embrace the west wind until you come to a wilderness.
在那里找一朵玫瑰。
Look for a rose there.
想要玫瑰吗?
Look for a rose?
这是第二次审判吗?
Is that the second trial?
你问去泽坦的路。
You asked the way to zetan.
还有其他人在我前面吗?
Are there others ahead of me?
你是第一个超过我的。
You are the first to pass me.
但其他探索者有其他的试验。
But other seekers have other trials.
我现在是拿着乞讨碗的乞丐了吗?
Am I a beggar with a begging bowl now?
我把你放进我的碗里!
L put you in my bowl!
我能为您效劳吗?
Can I help you?
要做什么?
To do what?
为什么?为了摆脱这个-?
Why? To get out of this-?
是谁这样折磨你?
Who's torturing you this way?
没有一个人。
No one.
那桶不是装满了油吗?
Isn't that barrel filled with oil?
当然可以。我自己加的。
Of course. I filled it myself.
我自己加的水，我自己进去的。你吗?
I filled it myself, and i got in it myself. You ?
我在这里已经十年了。
L've been in here ten years.
但是为什么呢?
But why?
为了摆脱我的下半身。
To rid myself of the bottom half of me.
现在已经所剩无几了。
There's very little left of it now.
你的腿看起来像海藻。
Your legs look like seaweed.
我希望如此。
I hope so.
那东西——我两腿之间那可怕的东西——现在差不多没了，是不是?
That thing- that terrible thing between my legs- it's almost gone now, isn't it?
只有丘疹。好。
A mere pimple. Good.
我希望它很快就会消失。
It'll go altogether soon, i hope.
十年!
Ten years!
你不吃东西怎么活?
How do you live without eating?
我的家人。他们给我带了一些米饭，一些水。
My family. They bring me a little rice, a little water.
你的家人怎么样?
Your family?
他们知道你把自己泡在油里了吗?
They know you're dissolving yourself in oil?
他们一开始不太高兴。
They weren't too happy about it at first.
尤其是我的妻子。
Especially my wife.
现在她明白。
Now she understands.
但是你为什么要-啊。
But why would you want to- ah.
你可以像我一样发誓保持贞洁。
You could have taken a vow of chastity, like I have.
我发誓保持贞洁。我发了十个誓言，一百个。
I took a vow of chastity. I took ten vows- a hundred.
一个人怎么可能是一个圣洁的人当他被那可怕的东西束缚在地上的时候?
How can a man be a holy man when that terrible thing attaches him to the earth?
我摆脱了我的钱，我脱掉了我的衣服，我每天吃一勺饭，我的思想开始翱翔。
I got rid of my money, i shed my clothes, I ate a spoonful of rice each day, and my mind began to soar.
我感受到了宇宙。
I felt the universe.
我就是宇宙。
I was the universe.
然后，那可怕的东西召唤了我。
And then, that terrible thing summoned me.
“你好!“这叫道。
“Hello!” it cried.
“想想这乐趣吧!”
“Think of the pleasure!”
有好几次，我抓了把刀。
several times, i grabbed a knife.
我打算一劳永逸地摆脱它。
I intended to rid myself of it once and for all.
但我，我是个懦夫。
But i- i was a coward.
然后……我找到办法了!
Then... I found a way!
我会把它和承载它的腿一起溶解掉。
I would dissolve it away and the legs that carried it along.
哦，你明显有精神问题。
Oh, you are obviously mentally disturbed.
嗯哼。你应该去看医生。
Mm-hmm. You should ha ve seen a doctor:
我是一个医生。
I am a doctor.
你发过贞洁的誓言。
You took a vow of chastity.
是的。
Yes.
你不会留着它的。
You won't keep it.
跟我来。
Come in here with me.
有足够的空间。我们将彼此相伴。
There's plenty of room. We'll keep each other company.
对不起，我得走了。我在找人。
L'm sorry, but I must go. I'm looking for someone.
谁?ζn。
Who? Zeta n.
再zetan !
Again zetan!
他们都来询问泽坦!
They all come around asking about zetan!
泽坦没有答案。
There is no answer in zetan.
答案就在我这里。
The answer is in here with me.
如果你不把它融化，就把它切下来!
Lf you won't melt it off, cut it off!
现在就做!不管你的梦想是什么，都会毁了它们!
Do it now! For whatever your dreams are, it will ruin them!
那可怕的东西就像一把剑!
It's like a sword, that terrible thing!
它会——它会把你切成碎片!
It will- it will cut you to pieces!
你吃了吗?
Have you eaten?
你的饮料吗?你的手是空的。
Where's your drink? Your hand is empty.
和平。
Peace.
别怪我!
Don't wish it on me!
全世界都在骚动，你却祝我平安!
The whole world is in commotion, and you wish me peace!
我不知道什么是和平。我不想要。
I don't know what peace is. I don't want it.
你不听沙漠的声音吗?
Don't you listen to the desert?
即使没有风，沙子也会歌唱。
Even when there's no wind, the sand sings.
我的名字是科德。
My name is cord.
哈!你看到了?cord!
Hah! You see? Cord!
玩的共鸣!打动!
Play a chord! Strike a chord!
连你的名字都是噪音!
Even your name is a noise!
你想要什么，科德?
What do you want, cord?
你想让我们耍你吗?
You want us to play on you?
我的妻子能让你的皮肤歌唱。
My wives can make your skin sing.
你是谁?
Who are you?
长沙。
Changsha.
我希望提供一切需要的东西。
It is my wish to provide everything that is needed.
告诉我你需要什么，科德，好让我为你提供幸福。
Tell me what you need, cord, that I may find happiness in providing it for you.
我寻找一朵玫瑰……在旷野。
I seek a rose... in the wilderness.
她叫塔拉。
Her name is Tara.
我的第九的妻子。
My ninth wife.
你可以带走她。
You may have her.
但我发誓要保持贞洁。
But I've taken a vow of chastity.
哈,哈!带走她将是双重牺牲。
Hah,hah! Well, taking her will be a twin sacrifice.
她向我许的愿，你向自己许的愿。
Her of her vows to me, and you of your vows to yourself.
我的第二个试验。是你吗?
My second trial. Is it with you?
也许。
Perhaps.
谁知道呢?
Who knows?
你知道吗?
Do you know?
嗯?
Huh?
我的朋友，你还需要用我来考验你自己吗?
Is it still your need, my friend, to test yourself against me?
这是我的需要。
It is my need.
那就伸出你的手，我的黑兄弟，因为你的感觉会满足你。
Then put out your hand, my black brother, for what you feel will satisfy you.
你来找我是为了考验自己，在失败中，你获得了胜利。
You came to me to test yourself, and in losing, you have gained your victory.
现在，你们正站在真理的门槛上。
For now, you are on the threshold of truth.
那种知识，那种天赋，那才是你真正想从我这里得到的
That knowledge- that gift, which is what you really want from me-
你现在有了。
you have it now.
我们什么时候打架?
When do we fight?
等我们睡着了，我的孩子。
After we sleep, my boy.
它让你开心?
It pleases you?
你在哪里?你不会受到伤害的。
- Where is your- - no harm will come to you.
我丈夫让我来找你。
My husband sent me to you.
他是zetan吗?
Is he zetan?
他是长沙。
He is changsha.
不是这本书的保管者?
Not the keeper of the book?
什么书?
What book?
他为什么派你来?
Why did he send you?
这不会违背你的誓言。
This will not violate your vow.
想要的水果不吃也可以享用。
The desired fruit may be enjoyed without consuming it.
我已经旅行很长时间了。
L've been traveling for a longtime.
休息。
Rest.
我一直在走一段在我掌心指明的旅程。
L've been taking a journey that was indicated in the palm of my hand.
你是我的审判，不是吗?
You're my trial, aren't you?
让我和你一起在你的掌心里走一会儿。
Let me walk the line in your palm with you for a moment.
不。
No.
我来告诉你。
Let me show you.
你要求和我一起走我的手掌心线。
You asked to walk the line of my palm with me.
你拒绝我!
You refused me!
你现在邀请我了吗?
Do you invite me now?
跟我一起走，但一会儿也不行。
Walk with me, but not for just a moment.
直到永远。
Forever.
Cord.
我和你一起去，但首先我们得休息。
L'll go with you, but first we must rest.
摆在我们面前的将是不容易的。
What lies ahead of us will not be easy.
泰拉?
Tara?
塔拉!
Tara!
不!
No!
长沙!
Changsha!
cord!我在这里。
Cord! I am here.
ζn ?
Zeta n ?
强于zetan。
Stronger than zetan.
死亡。我了解你。
Death. I kno w you.
你怎么这么丑?
Why are you so ugly?
还是每个男人的脸都不一样?
Or do you have a different face for every man?
我要跪下吗?
Shall I go to my knees?
你是在等恐惧冻结我的心再把它挖出来吗?
Are you waiting for fear to freeze my heart before you carve it out?
很快,cord!很快!
Soon, cord! Soon!
欢迎客人随时光临。
Come anytime, welcome guest.
这是不可能的。
It can't be done.
你做不到。
You can't do it.
不能做什么?
Can't do what?
你不可能在同一块水上踩两次。
You can't step twice on the same piece of water.
一条鱼曾经救过我的命。
A fish saved my life once.
如何?我吃了他。
How? I ate him.
你失明多久了?
How long have you been blind?
-我又不是瞎子。我是- - - ?
- I'm not blind. - Am I?
你用问题来回答每个问题吗?
Do you answer every question with a question?
你会质疑每个答案吗?
Do you question every answer?
和你说话就像对着墙说话。
Talking to you is like talking to a wall.
有一次，佛陀坐在一堵墙前，当他起身时，他就开悟了。
Buddha once sat before a wall, and when he arose, he was enlightened.
你会把自己和佛陀比较吗?
Do you compare yourself with Buddha?
哈,哈,没有;只对着墙。
Hah, hah, no; Only to the wall.
你还没告诉我你的第二次审判。
You have not told me of your second trial.
这不是审判。
It wasn't a trial.
这是一个教训。
It was a lesson.
教我吧。
Teach it to me.
啊，你知道的。
Ah, you know it.
你似乎什么都知道。
You seem to know everything.
每天早晨，当我醒来时，就像一个上第一节课的学者一样，我准备着空白的头脑，准备着这一天的写作。
Each morning when I awake, like a scholar at his first class, I prepare a blank mind for the day to write upon.
一年前，我立下了贞洁的誓言。
A year ago i took a vow of chastity.
一天前我把它弄坏了。
A day ago I broke it.
很高兴，因为我意识到我们生来就是爱的。
Gladly, because I realized we are born to love.
但我当时做的事比任何愚蠢的誓言都要糟糕。
But what I did then was worse than taking any foolish vow.
我试图拥有我所爱的。
I tried to possess what I loved.
那时我才知道，把爱的怀抱抱得太紧
I didn't know then that the embrace of love held too tightly
能毁掉你爱的人。
can destroy the one you love.
Cord.
流逝的每一刻都在改变着你。
Each moment that passes changes you.
你甚至不能拥有你自己。
You do not- cannot possess even yourself.
你怎么能希望拥有任何人或任何东西?
How can you hope to possess anyone or anything else?
我现在意识到你是我隐藏的老师。
I realize now you are my hidden teacher.
如果我想在下一次的考验中幸存下来，我必须被允许跟随你并学习。
And if I am to survive the next trial, i must be allowed to follow you and to learn.
你永远也忍受不了。我会的。
You will never endure it. I will.
我吗?
Will I?
哈，哈，告诉我为什么我不能忍受。
Hah, hah, tell me why i won't be able to endure it.
你永远不会有耐心。在你了解事物的含义之前，你就会对它们进行判断。什么东西?
You will never have the Patience. You will see things and judge them before you know what they mean. What things?
你看到了什么?你在事情发生之前就开始问。
You see? You ask what things even before the things have happened.
我无法理解你的不耐烦。
Your impatience is beyond me.
我会耐心等待。我将成为一个空容器!
I'll be patient. I'll be an empty vessel!
有一个条件。
One condition.
任何东西。
Anything.
在我亲自给你答复之前，你不要问任何事情。
You must ask nothing about any event until such time as i myself give you an answer.
同意了。
Agreed.
我们想过你的河。
We wish to cross your river.
我们俩的车费是多少?
What is the fare for the two of us?
你看起来不像有钱。
You don't look as if you have money.
啊!啊!这样的报酬够吗?
Ah! Ah! Will this be payment enough?
啊哈。
Aha.
是的，是的，这就行了。
Yes, yes, this will do.
等等，你这个老傻瓜!让我看看。
Wait, you old fool! Let me see.
这是毫无价值的。如果你想过河，就游过去。
It's worthless. If you want to cross the river, swim.
停止!这是一个诚实的人。
Stop that! This is an honest man.
好像你在床上是个好男人，你这个笨蛋!
Like you are a good man in bed, you silly stick!
没有钱，就没有交通工具。
No money, no transportation.
这是我的船!我将决定。
It is my boat! I will decide.
你的船吗?你可怜的儿子和我的。
Your boat? Your poor son's and mine.
什么时候变成你的了?
Since when is it yours?
自从我嫁给你，你这个笨蛋!
Since I married you, you ignoramus!
我不是用我的身体作为礼物吗?还有一个男孩的祝福?
Didn't I pay for it with the gift of my body... And the blessing of a boy child?
哈!20年来你给我的礼物是830英镑!
Hah! The gift you gave me once twenty yea rs 830!
你想怎么把船弄回来，白痴?你什么都不想。
How do you expect to get the boat back, you idiot? You never think of nothing.
那个可怜的男人。
That poor man.
他很高兴,快乐吗?
He's happy- happy?
他身上的每根骨头都充满了痛苦。
There's misery in every bone in his body.
不怕死的人不就是幸福的人吗?
Is not a happy man one who does not fear death?
他不仅不害怕，他的日子充满了期待它的快乐。
Not only does he not fear it, his days are filled with joy looking forward to it.
你为什么这么做?
Why'd you do that?
他想帮助我们。你就是这样报答他的吗?
He wanted to help us. Ls that how you repay him?
你毁了他的生计。
You've destroyed his livelihood.
他现在对她毫无防备了。
He'll be defenseless against her now.
我就说你会妄下结论。
I told you you would jump to conclusions.
-你在干什么?——隐藏。
- What are you doing? - Hiding.
这里没什么好隐瞒的。
There's nothing here to hide from.
还没有。
Not yet.
啊!他们见过你。
Ah! They've seen you.
我从没想过你会逃避战斗。
I never thought you'd run from a fight.
用笛子很难杀死一匹马。
Lt's hard to kill a horse with a flute.
为什么你一定要选择现在去做好事?
Why do you have to pick now to do good deeds?
你觉得内疚，因为你踢翻了船夫的船，所以你要自杀。
You're feeling guilty because you kicked in the ferryman's boat, so you're committing suicide.
你不仅是个傻瓜，你还不能信守诺言。
You're not only a fool, you can't keep a promise.
承诺什么?你说过你会把舌头扯出来
What promise? You said you would tear out your tongue-
烟囱也坏了。我们可以解决。
the chimney's broken too. We could fix that.
屋顶需要修理。
And the roof needs mending.
我想跟你道别。
L'm thinking of saying good-bye.
再见。
Good-bye.
我曾疯狂地相信你是我的老师。
I was crazy to believe you were my teacher.
学会倾听别人没有说出来的话。
Learn to listen to that which is not spoken.
我听腻了你的谜语。
L'm tired of your riddles.
刚才发生的事没有任何教训。
There was no lesson in what just happened.
我只看到一个傻子邀请刺客来杀他。
All I saw was a fool inviting his assassins to kill him.
傻瓜是聪明人的孪生兄弟。
The fool is the twin of the wise.
啊。
Ah.
你不可能两次踩在同一块水上，两只被绑在一起的鸟有四只翅膀，但不能飞，而且——而且——蝌蚪失去了力量，剑也不能割伤自己。
And you can't step on the same piece of water twice, and two birds tied together have four wings but cannot fly, and- and- and the tadpole loses its strength, and the sword can't cut itself.
一旦目标出现在眼前，路径和通道就没有意义了。
The path and the gateway have no use or meaning once the objective is in sight.
马没有乳房，牛不会嘶鸣，上是下，侧是正对。
And a horse has no udders, and a cow can't whinny, and up is down, and sideways is straight ahead.
噢,看。看。
Oh, look. Look.
他们是谁?噢'。
Who are they? Ow'.?
先生,请。你有硬币吗?
Mister, please. Do you have a coin?
硬币!硬币!请。
Coin! Coin! Please.
为什么?
Why?
这次我要走了。
This time I'm leaving.
你必须停止承诺。
You must stop making promises.
这不仅仅是一个承诺。
This is more than a promise.
现在我摆脱了你，我可以问问题了。
Now that I'm free of you, I'm free to ask questions.
解释你自己。
Explain yourself.
你踢进渡船是什么意思?
What did you mean by kicking in the ferryboat?
我们两个中，你是瞎的那个。
Of the two of us, you are the one who is blind.
被你所看到的蒙蔽了双眼。
Blinded by what you see.
我要的是答案，不是这些哲学。
I want an answer, not all this philosophy.
我把船弄坏了，因为如果我不这样做，士兵们就会用它过河，老人和他的家人就会被杀死。
I damaged the boat because if I hadn't, the soldiers would have used it to cross the river, and the old man and all his family would have been killed.
也许是为了获得幸福。
Achieving his happiness, perhaps.
但是你怎么知道士兵来了?
But how did you know the soldiers were coming?
-你听到了吗?——没有。
- Did you hear them? - No.
石头墙。你为什么停下来修理它?
The stone wall. Why did you stop to repair it?
有一袋硬币露出了一部分在石头里。
There was a bag of coins partly exposed in the stones.
我修复了城墙，这样士兵就不会发现并偷走它，让寡妇和她的孩子们没有经济来源。
I repaired the wall so the soldiers wouldn't find it and steal it, leaving the widow and her children without means.
你看不到包。你闻到了吗?
You couldn't see the bag. Did you smell it?
不。
No.
这个男孩。解释这个男孩。
The boy. Explain the boy.
这个男孩。
The boy.
你残害了那个男孩。你打断了他的鼻子，一个漂亮的男孩。
You mutilated the boy. You broke his nose, a beautiful boy.
太漂亮了。
Too beautiful.
他是个暴君。他长大后会变得更糟。
He was a tyrant. He would have grown up to be worse.
我把他的父母从他的美貌中解放出来。
I freed his parents from their bondage to his beauty.
哈!你连他的脸都没摸。
Hah! You didn't even touch his face.
你怎么知道他长什么样?你感觉到了吗?
How'd you know what he looked like? Dio' you sense it?
不。但我也救了他的父母和那男孩，现在，我让你摆脱了我。
No. But I freed his parents and the boy too, and now, I free you of me.
我还没说完呢。
Well, I haven't finished yet.
你没有听到士兵的声音，你没有闻到袋子的味道，你没有感觉到那个男孩。
You didn't hear the soldiers, and you didn't smell the bag, and you didn't sense the boy.
我需要一个解释。
I want an explanation.
我知道。
I knew.
如何?
How?
你以前来过这里!
You were through here before!
多少次?
How many times?
这是什么?
What is this?
Cord?
哈，哈，是，cord!
Hah, hah, yes, cord!
我在荒野里款待的那个人。
The man I entertained in the wilderness.
同样的cord，是的。
The very same cord, yes.
不，不一样了。
No, not the same.
不完全是。
Not quite.
但你要找的仍然是- n。
But you're still looking for the same- zeta n.
哈!是的。
Hah! Yes.
ζn。
Zeta n.
他很近了。
He's very near.
哦。非常非常近了。
Oh. Very, very near.
你要做的就是从我身边过去。
All you have to do is pass by me.
我和你没有矛盾。
I have no quarrel with you.
没有争吵?
No quarrel?
哈，哈，可是你的爱情呢，塔拉?
Hah, hah, but what of your love, Tara?
我不是把塔拉钉死在十字架上了吗?
Did I not crucify Tara?
不。
No.
但是我自己，用这两只手——不，我自己，用这两只手。
But I myself, with these two hands- no, I myself, with these two hands.
不是同一个cord。
Not the same cord.
所以你不用仇恨来对抗我。
So, you do not confront me with hate.
不。
No.
那为什么还要跟我对质
Then why confront me at all?
加入我。
Join me.
牵起我的手。
Take my hand.
我可以带你去一个没有夜晚和克莱的世界。
Ah, I can show you a world where you will find no night or Clay.
太阳永远不会升起或落下。
The sun will never rise or set.
我的目标是泽坦。
My goal is zetan.
啊,是的。
Ah, yes.
在黎明。
At daybreak then.
沿着海滩。
Along the beach.
不。
No.
现在。
Now.
嗯?
Huh?
不是同一个cord。
Not the same cord.
你的路要跨过水面。
Your way lies across the water.
你是被选中的。
You are the chosen.
你在寻找泽坦。
You have sought zetan.
Zetan在这里。
Zetan is here.
我亲爱的cord
My dear cord.
我很高兴见到你。
I am so pleased to see you.
这里的土壤对香水的作用非同一般。
Extraordinary what the soil here does for the perfume.
请。
Please.
他们是谁?
Who are they?
它们是最接近的。
They are the near ones.
他们在研究完美的完善。
They are studying the perfecting of perfection.
你是他们的老师吗?
Are you their teacher?
不,不是真的。
No, not really.
我们发现，最好的方法就是让老师，也就是学生，一起进行教学。
We have found that the best way is for the teacher, so called, and the student to produce the teaching together.
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
是的，听起来很合理。
Yes, it sounds reasonable.
有什么事困扰你吗，科德?
Is something disturbing you, cord?
不。
No.
你似乎有些困惑。
You seem somewhat puzzled.
我想知道我们什么时候吵架。
I want to know when we fight.
谁?
Who?
你和我
You and I.
关于什么?
About what?
这本书。
The book.
永恒的书。
The everlasting book.
很好。
Very well.
我们去阳台，在仪式上给你们排练。
We will go to the terrace and rehearse you in the ceremony.
什么仪式?
What ceremony?
在你存在之前的那个人，被任命为这本书的守护者。
The one that precedes your being made the keeper of the book.
等等!等等!我不明白你的意思。
Wait! Wait! I don't understand.
这是和谐之座，cord。
This is the seat of Harmony, cord.
在我看来，这个岛上只有哈莫尼。
There seems to me to be nothing but Harmony on this island.
是的，它渗透到这里的一切。
Yes, it, uh, permeates everything here.
试试座椅，cord。来吧，试试。
Try the seat, cord. Go on, try it.
你能看到你的未来吗，科德?
Can you see your future, cord?
无尽的宁静。
Endless clays of peace.
还有人能有更多的愿望吗?
Ls there any man who can wish for more?
请书。
The book, please.
这本书。
The book.
我相信你经受过很多考验。
You have survived several trials, I am sure.
他们一定很可怕，但你现在要看到的可能更令人担忧。
Very frightening they must have been, but what you are about to see now may be even more alarming.
你可以代替我，科德，不用看书，就像我多年前那样。
You can take my place here, cord, without looking into the book, just as I did many years ago.
我必须先看看。
I must look first.
探索者们一路战斗到这里，年复一年，愿意，渴望付出可怕的代价来看看那本书里的内容。
The seekers fight their way here, year after year, willing, eager to pay a terrible price to see what is in that book.
当他们满怀着寻找生命中所有问题的答案的强烈期望，把它打开时，他们发现了什么?
And when they fling it open in blazing expectation of finding all the answers to all life's questions, what do they find?
他们自己。
Themselves.
没有书，cord。
There is no book, cord.
没有外在的启迪。
No enlightenment outside yourself.
没有什么可收回的了?
There is nothing to take back?
不。
No.
他们大多数人都在这里。
They are here, most of them.
其他人已经回到这个世界，以各种各样的伪装，他们提供了你所经历过的考验。
Others have gone back into the world, and in all manner of disguises, they have provided the trials such as you have experienced.
一些成为教师。
Some become teachers.
其中一个吹的笛子只有我能听到!
And one of them plays a flute that only I can hear!
我在你这么大的时候被派去找这本书，我成了守护者。
I was your age when i was sent to find the book, and I became the keeper.
现在你，cord，你可以做守护者。
Now you, cord- you can be the keeper.
你会享受它——无尽的宁静和快乐!
You will enjoy it- the endless peace and pleasure!
释放我,cord!
Release me, cord!
释放我。
Release me.
你已经看过那本书了，科德。
You've looked at the book, cord.
是的。
Yes.
你看到了什么?
And what did you see?
一切。
Everything.